跟你说  威尔  选这个肯定没错
Telling you, Will, you got a real winner here.
她肯定会喜欢的
She's just gonna love it.
斯泰茜  装盒吧
Stacy, box her up.
只要盒子就够了
Oh, just the box.
肯定比包装纸好看多了
I'm sure it's prettier than the paper.
这么一颗小钻石
One tiny rock.
够给我自己买许多好东西呢
So many other cool things I could have bought for myself.
萨姆  斯泰茜
Sam, Stacy,
很高兴被你们"喜结"一空
it's been a pleasure being "ripped" off by you.
多好一小伙
Such a nice boy.
可惜得拄拐
Too bad he's a handicap.
借过
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还好吗  兄弟  放轻松
You all right, man? Take it easy, man!
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
总监：
zlean
小伙子有糖尿病眼病
Kid's a blind diabetic.
他处于高血糖高渗状态
He's hyperglycemic hyperosmolar.
在他的血检结果出来前我们是这么想的
Which is what we thought until his blood tests showed
可是结果显示血糖水平尚可且酮体阴性
a controlled sugar level and no ketones.
可能是由吸毒引起的
It could be caused by drug abuse.
毒理分析显示他没有吸毒
His tox scenens were clean.
你个谎话精
You lying sack of crap.
检查报告就在我手里
I have them right in front of me.
不是说你
Not you.
这次
This time.
是我原最铁哥们
My former BFF.
他在放暗箭
He's s-m-i-t-b-a-w-s,
在我们说话间在我背后捅我一刀
stabbing me in the back as we speak.
你人在哪里啊
Where exactly are you?
要是有人问起
If anyone should happen to ask,
就说我在州外参加
I'm in an out-of-state
医学会议  什么时候回来另行通知
Medical conference until further notice.
为什么会...
Why would any--
也不重要
And...don't really care.
幻听
Auditory hallucinations
定向障碍可能是精神分裂症表现
and disorientation could be signs of schizophrenia.
做过精神病鉴定了
They did a psych consult.
精神情况正常
Mental status is normal.
癫痫  噪声性癫痫
Seizure, noise-induced epilepsy--
可能由交通高峰期的噪音引发
The sound of rush hour traffic could have set it off.
做个脑电图
Run an EEG.
进行脑部谐波测试来找出原因
Blast his brain with harmonics to find out.
还有  要是有人深入寻问
Also, if anyone should further happen to ask,
就说我去年和一群无国界医生
I spent the whole last year in Africa
待在非洲
with doctors without boundaries.
你在躲谁啊
Who are you hiding from?
灾祸
Evil.
豪斯在哪
Where's House?
他在参加州外的一次医学会议
Uh, he's at an out-of-state medical conference
在巴尔的摩
in Baltimore,
我记得
I think.
很高兴见到你们
Nice to meet you.
我是布莱思  他母亲
I'm Blythe, his mother.
要不要我去你公寓把盲点打字机
Do you want me to pick up the braille writer
和笔记本电脑拿来
and laptop from your apartment?
我可没打算在这长住
I don't plan on being here that long.
我昨天没吃午饭
I didn't eat lunch yesterday.
可能就是饿昏了
I probably just fainted.
或者是癫痫发作
Or had an epileptic seizure.
这是一种可能
Which is only one possibility.
我是奇斯医生
I'm Dr. Chase.
我们想和你单独聊聊你的病情
Uh, we'd like to discuss your case with you privately.
我是他女朋友  能留下来听吗
I'm his girlfriend. Is it all right If I stay for this?
梅丽莎可以留下
Melissa can stay.
我以前从来没有发作过癫痫
And I've never had a seizure before in my life.
可能是轻微型癫痫
They can be mild,
表现为无法集中注意力
like a loss of concentration
或是肌肉抖动
or a muscle tremor.
通常病人家属会比病人自己先注意到这些
A lot of times a family member notices before the patient does.
顺便说一下  我是朴克医生
I'm Dr. Park, by the way.
我1米58  亚裔  如果你要摸我的脸
I'm 5'2", Asian, and I'm totally cool with it
我不会介意的
if you wanna feel my face.
只有电影里的盲人才会那么做
Blind people only do that in movies.
但你听起来人很好  所以如果你想让我摸
But you sound nice, so if you want me to...
她的意思是  也许你没感觉癫痫发作
Her point was, you may not have realized you having a seizure,
但是可能你女朋友注意到了
but maybe your girlfriend has.
没有
No.
我已经有五个月没见他了
But I--I haven't seen him for the last five months.
我们暂时分开了一段时间
We were on a break.
就像《老友记》里的瑞秋和罗斯那样
Like Rachel and Ross on Friends.
我从没看过那部剧  但听说很不错
Never seen the show myself, but I hear it's good.
这玩笑让我那些盲人朋友乐翻了
That joke usually kills my blind friends.
威尔  你的病是件很严肃的事
Will, this is serious.
不是的
No, it's not,
因为我压根没有癫痫
since I don't have epilepsy.
我得时刻注意
I have to pay attention to every signal
身体发出或者接受到的任何信号
my body sends or receives,
否则我就会睡在垃圾堆里了
or I end up taking a dirt nap.
你们真的以为我会不知道自己有没有癫痫吗
You don't think I'd know if I was having seizures?
可能只是血糖偏低了
It's probably just low blood sugar.
如果是那样的话  你应该
If that's true, then you shouldn't have
能顺利通过检查
a problem passing our test.
他过得怎么样  詹姆斯  你说实话
How is he, James, really?
他很好  我很久都没见他这么好了
He's better than I've seen him in a long time.
他幸福吗
Is he happy?
没事的
It's ok.
他一直就是个很复杂的孩子
He's always been a complicated child.
你最近进过医院吗
Were you in the hospital recently?
不是什么大病
Oh, nothing serious.
我昨天刚移除掉几颗痣
I just had a few moles removed yesterday
都忘了还戴着这个东西
and forgot I even had it on.
如果格雷戈突然提前从会上回来了
Look, if Greg happens to get back early from the conference,
之后三天我都在城里的酒店住着
I'm staying at a hotel in town for the next three days.
我希望他能给我打个电话
I would like him to call me.
我会转告他的
I will pass it on.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们这能不能续杯
Um, do you think that they would mind
好带着路上喝
if I got a refill for the road?
-可以啊  -好的
- Not at all. - Good.
给低频音
Not seeing any seizure actityty
未见癫痫发作征象
in response to low frequency sounds.
现在给中频音
I'm starting him on mid-range.
你瞧见他女朋友了吗
Have you seen his girlfriend?
相当漂亮
Extremely hot.
盲人就不能有个漂亮女友吗
Blind people can't have attractive girlfriends?
我不是这意思
Not my point.
他竟然劝他女友
He actually convinced her to go for
和自己暂时分开
the whole relationship break thing.
你怎么知道那不是她的意思
How do you know it wasn't her idea?
因为她回到他身边了
Because she's back with him.
女人提出分手是因为她们想分手
Women suggest a break when they wanna break up.
而男人要分手是因为他们想
Men do it because they wanna have sex
在安定生活前和别的女人们滚床单
with other women before they settle down.
他们现在结婚有点早  你说呢
They're a little young to get married, don't you think?
我结婚时就这么大
I was their age when I did.
我明白你的意思了
I see your point.
他在抽搐
He's seizing.
音频在三百赫兹
Sound frequency's at 300 hertz.
不是癫痫
It's not a seizure.
脑电图无异常波形
He's not spiking on his EEG.
他没有呼吸了
He's not moving air.
可能被什么东西呛住了
I think he's choking on something.
有血
Blood.
我没看见有什么阻挡物啊
I don't see any blockage.
帮我给他挪个地方
Help me move him.
放松  呼吸
Just relax and breathe.
这是什么
What--what are these?
下颚三颗牙齿脱落
Three teeth detached from his jawbone
并卡在咽部
and lodged in his throat.
他差点被呛死
He almost choked to death on them.
环境因素呢
Environmental?
可能是重金属中毒
Could be heavy metal poisoning
或暴露于辐射中
or radiation exposure.
那他就不会是唯一的受害者
Then he wouldn't be the only one.
他是名会计
He's an accountant who works
与五十多个人在同一楼层工作
on the same floor with 50 other people.
也许是他女朋友下的毒
Maybe his girlfriend poisoned him.
豪斯就会赞成这个猜测
House usually thinks that's a good guess.
她肯定很生气  而且毫无自尊
And she's gotta be pissed off and have low self-esteem.
不然的话
Why else would she
她为何会允许他去勾搭其他女人
give him a free pass to pork other women?
因为他拄拐
Because he's handicapped.
女人会对我们同情心泛滥
Women feel sorry for us.
我的拐杖就是免罪牌
This cane is tail bait.
你现在在哪呢
Where are you now?
你还指望他会回答吗
Expect an actual answer this time?
嗨  大家好
Hi, guys.
豪斯的母亲离开了吗
Was wondering if House's mother left yet.
他不让我去医...
He won't let me go to a hos--
不是环境原因  是牙周炎
It's not environmental, it's periodontitis.
口腔感染不能解释他的定向障碍
An oral infection doesn't explain his disorientation
以及幻听
and auditory hallucinations.
孩子都在笑你
They're laughing because they know
他们都知道糖尿病会使病情恶化
diabetes exacerbates the condition.
可能引发全身表现
It could progress to a systemic disease.
细菌播散至其他器官
The bacteria spread and affect other organs.
比如大脑
Like his brain.
给他用广谱抗生素
Start him on broad spectrum antibiotics
再请口腔科会诊
and book him an appointment with a periodontist.
他现在假孩子都要有了吗
He has fake children now, too?
你觉得我入不了你母亲的眼吗
You think I'm not good enough for your mother.
别在孩子面前吵  亲爱的
Not in front of the kids, honey.
再加几只飞虫  添上一两头傻羊
Hey, add a couple of flies, toss in a dead goat or two,
你就能胜出了
we might have a winner.
她走了吗
She gone?
走了
Yeah.
我们真的要谈一谈
We really need to talk.
好吧
Okay.
放下蜡笔
Crayons down.
想拿零花钱  就排好队
Line up if you wanna get paid.
这将是我唯一一次成功地骗过我妈
It's the only time I ever successfully lie to my mom.
要精心准备
Through the elaborate preparations
还要有道具
and props.
你你你
Hey, hey, hey.
我说了不要变形金刚  小滑头
I said no transformers, slick.
待在这  直到警报解除
Stay here until the coast is clear.
好吧
Fine.
不过今晚你睡沙发
But you sleep on couch tonight.
你跟她一起住吗
You sleeping with her now?
以防移民局的人翻窗进来检查
Just in case an I.N.S. guy comes in through the window.
她也不相信
Yeah, she didn't buy it either.
你要找你母亲谈一谈
You need to talk to your mother.
等我准备好
When I'm ready.
还要搞本假护照
Still need to get a fake passport,
假照片  还要借个艾滋病病人
doctored photos, maybe a case of AIDS.
她病了  豪斯
She's sick, House.
她自己说的吗
Did she say that?
她戴着住院病人手腕标识
She was wearing a hospital admission bracelet
随身带着本关于如何渡过癌症晚期的书
and carrying around a book on dealing with terminal cancer.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
接下来三天  她都住在格兰德酒店
She's staying at The Grand for the next three days.
抗生素可控制感染
The antibiotics will stop the infection
阻止其播散
from spreading further.
明天牙周病医生会给你一番说教
And I'll spare you the lecture you'll get
我就不再折磨你了
from the periodontist tomorrow,
但你确实需要注意口腔卫生
but you need to practice better oral hygiene.
你们是说我会病成这样是因为
So are you guys saying this is happening because, what,
-我总不用牙线吗  -我这么说也许没帮助
- I didn't floss enough? - Probably didn't help,
但糖尿病病人易受此类感染
but diabetics are prone to this type of infection.
这么久以来  他睡觉前
Half the time, he doesn't even bother
常常连衣服都懒得脱
getting undressed before he goes to bed.
这就不难想象  你大概总是
Can only imagine how many times you've skipped
忘记刷牙  自从...
brushing your teeth since we...
对不起
Sorry.
我并不是想说教  宝贝
I don't mean to lecture you, babe.
但我想你是对的
Well, I guess you're right.
你一整天都没吃东西
Look, you haven't eaten anything all day.
要不你先去填填肚子吧
Why don't you go grab a bite?
我没事
I'll be fine.
好的  那我们一小时后再见
All right, well, I'll see you in an hour, okay?
除非我先看见你[好不让你见着]
Not if I see you first.
我在想  你们能不能帮我个忙
I was wondering if I could ask you guys for a favor.
我急需我的笔记本和盲点打字机
I really need my laptop and braille writer,
而我不能让梅丽莎帮我去拿
and I can't ask Melissa to get them for me.
为什么不能
Why not?
因为...
Because...
我想让你们帮我把这个藏好
I want you to put this someplace safe.
好美啊
It's beautiful.
人们总是说钻石很美
People always say diamonds are beautiful.
但对我来说  它们冷冰冰的
But to me they just feel cold.
边缘非常尖锐
They have really sharp edges.
我猜你说服她暂时分开  是件好事
I guess convincing her to take a break was a good thing.
分开是她的主意
Well, the break was her idea.
梅丽莎是我唯一一个交往过的女孩
Melissa is the only girl I've ever dated.
她希望在我们更进一步前
She wanted me to be sure before we
我能确定自己的心
took the next step.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
来都来了
We're here.
最好顺便搜查一番
We might as well search the place
以防牙周炎这个诊断是错的
in case we're wrong about periodontitis.
你又在干什么
What are you doing?
来都来了  顺便吃点
We're here, might as well eat.
你这是在偷一个瞎子的食物
You're stealing food from a blind man?
我们是在帮他  这是他欠我的
We're doing him a favor. He owes me.
根据你那"毫无自尊"理论
I take it from your low self-esteem theory
我猜你曾有类似的分手经历
you have some experience with relationship breaks?
怎么回事
What happened?
他说服我暂时分开  然后...
He talked me into it, then...
就和我的三个朋友上了床
slept with three of my friends.
然后又甩了我
Then dumped my ass.
大学时的男友
College boyfriend.
以为他是我的真爱
Thought he was the love of my life.
那你为何要同意分开呢
Then why agree to a break?
我当时没什么自尊
My self-esteem wasn't as high back then.
没有人有
No one's is.
恶
Oh!
无糖的
Sugar free!
难吃死了
Disgusting!
我去检查浴室  你继续找零食吧
I'll check the bathroom. You keep check the snacks.
格雷戈
Greg.
抱歉我没先打声招呼
Sorry I didn't call first.
我刚从会上飞回来
I just flew back from my conference.
这会...这会儿真的不太...
This--this really isn't, uh--
给我你的医疗记录
I need your medical records
以及主治医生的姓名
and the name of your primary physician.
你记得贝尔先生吧
Well, you remember Mr. Bell.
即便不记得  这下也不会忘了
Well, if I didn't, I will now.
你并没有病危
You're not dying?
让詹姆斯看到癌症的书
I, uh...I may have mislead James
可能是我误导他了
by letting him see a book on cancer.
但是我们希望的是
We did, however, have some expectations
你会先打个电话
that you might call first.
是啊
Yeah.
我没设想你会通过这样的方式知道
This isn't how I envisioned you finding out.
我和贝尔先生  我们
Mr. Bell and I, we're...
在做爱  我懂的
Having sex, got it.
还结婚了
Getting married. Also.
我们希望你是第一个知道的
We wanted you to be the first to know.
注射十毫克地西泮
I need 10 milligrams of benzodiazepine.
帮我压住他
Help me hold him down.
我要将癫痫重新写上白板
I'm putting epilepsy back on the table.
我要把它去掉
And I'm taking it off because
因为解释不了他为什么掉牙齿
it doesn't explain losing his teeth.
病人患有糖尿病
The kid's diabetic.
可能确实患有牙周炎但与病情无关
The periodontitis could be real but completely unrelated.
还真是巧啊  你觉得呢  豪斯
Coincidence. Buying that, House?
等我摆脱今天下午受到的
Until I hear something that takes my mind off
令人蛋疼的精神创伤  再说吧
the jurassic schlong that I was traumatized by this afternoon.
我知道病人是怎么了
I know what's wrong with the patient.
违禁毒品  酸中毒
Illegal drugs. Some kind of acid.
他的毒理检查显示没问题
His tox screens were clean.
他的公寓就不是那么回事了
His apartment wasn't.
我们没有发现毒品啊
We didn't find any drugs.
那为什么我现在嗨了呢
Then why am I completely tripping balls right now?
伙计们  我真的很害怕
I'm seriously freaking out here, guys.
你们看不出来吗
Can't you tell?
你看着和平时没什么两样啊
You pretty much look the same as you always do.
把眼镜摘掉
Take your glasses off.
瞳孔扩大
Pupils dilated...
脉搏加速  有幻觉吗
Pulse elevated. Hallucinating?
有的吧  因为
I think so, because...
他是只兔子
He's a rabbit.
啊  我懂了
Oh, I get it.
她是他老婆
Because she's his wife.
他们经常调情  我看到过的
They flirt a lot. I've seen things.
陶博  陶博看着不是
Mm, Taub-- Taub is either...
牙仙就是彩虹仙子
a tooth fairy or... rainbow brite.
还有你
And you...
你就是豪斯
you're just House.
她吃了病人公寓里的
She ate ice cream and gummi bears
冰淇淋和软糖
at the patient's apartment.
其中肯定有一样被下了药
One of 'em must have been dosed with it.
回去找那些毒品  你们俩
Go back and find the drugs. You two,
弄清楚他在哪里买的
find out where he bought them,
给他做脑部核磁共振
and then MRI his brain.
查看有没有感染  团块和斑块
Check for infections, masses, and plaques.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
回头再告诉你
We'll get back to you on that.
我生下来就是个盲人
I've been blind since birth.
我想也许试试迷幻药
I thought maybe if I tried LSD,
我可能看见  颜色  形状
I might, you know... Colors...A shape.
我只是
I just--
只是想看看这个世界
I just wanted to see something.
-多少次  -五六次吧
- How many times? - Maybe five or six.
我们得知道你在哪里买的
We need to know where you bought it
以便我们分析其中的成分
so we can find out what was in it.
我女朋友给我的
My girlfriend gave it to me.
-我去找她  -不  别去
- I'll find her. - No, don't.
不是  不是梅丽莎
It--it wasn't Melissa.
我遇到了别的人
I met someone else.
你打算什么时候告诉她呢
When were you planning on telling her that,
求婚之前还是求婚之后呢
before or after you ask her to marry you?
戒指不是给她的
The ring isn't for her.
我们当时分手了
We were on a break.
她想让我看看外面的世界
She wanted me to see what else was out there,
我照做了
and I did.
那天我打算告诉她的
I was gonna tell her the other night,
结果却进医院了
but I ended up here instead.
我们需要和给你药的人谈谈
We just need to talk to the one who supplied the drugs.
她和她的父母去度假了
She's on vacation with her parents.
这是她的联系方式
This is her cell.
我不想让她知道我在医院
I don't want her to know I'm in the hospital.
她会吓傻掉的
She'll only freak out.
你还真是体贴啊
That's very considerate of you.
你以为我就容易吗
You think this is easy for me.
我知道我必须告诉梅丽莎
I know I have to tell Melissa.
那怎么还不说呢
Well, what's stopping you?
她仍然是我的好朋友
She's still one of my best friends.
我不想独自一人待在医院
And I don't want to be alone in here.
见过你母亲了吗
Have you seen your mother yet?
她没有快死了
She's not dying.
她在和我父亲做爱
She was having sex with my father.
忽略她  她酸中毒
Ignore her. She's on acid.
你父亲已经死了  豪斯
Your father's dead, House.
不是那位逝者老爹  是我生父
Not the dead dad, the biological dad.
就是在逝者老爹葬礼上指给你看的那人
The one I pointed out to you at fake father's funeral.
好吧
Huh.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你唯一的证据就是你十二岁时
Your only evidence is that birthmark you saw
看到的胎记
when you were 12.
好吧  我现在看到了第二个胎记
Well, now I've seen two.
好消息是我做不了多久的
Good news is I won't technically be a bastard
"混蛋"了
much longer.
我们即将组成一个畸形的家庭
We're gonna be one big crappy family.
好吧  这  这是个好消息
Well, that's-- that's great news.
你母亲不会再孑然一身了
Your mother won't be alone anymore,
你也可以了解那个人了
and you can finally get to know the guy.
是啊  这倒也是
Yes, that is one option.
你难道就一点不好奇吗
Are you saying you're not even curious?
你知道我怎么看吗
You want to know what I think?
我想你知道答案的吧
I think you know the answer to that question.
你对你母亲避而不见是因为
You avoid your mother because she's the one person
你唯一在乎的就是你母亲的看法
whose opinion you actually care about.
如果真是这么回事的话  你就该闭嘴了
If that was true, you'd have every reason to shut up.
我对我母亲避而不见是因为她很无趣
I avoid my mother because she's boring.
所以你对坐牢和与陌生人结婚
That's why you've been so open and honest
抱着开放坦然的态度
about prison and marrying a complete stranger.
即便我在意她的看法
Even if I care what she thinks,
我为什么要在意精子捐献者的看法呢
why would I care what some sperm donor does?
他的书你读了三遍
You read the guy's book about three times.
陈芝麻烂谷子的事了
Years ago.
因为书写得很差才要看了三遍
It took three times because it was so badly written.
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
第二个胎记在他的小弟弟上  对吧
The second birthmark was on his penis, right?
他是个混蛋
He's a dick.
你在豪斯手下工作了几个月了
You've been working for House for months
现在才意识到
and just now realized
残疾人也可能是混蛋  是不是太迟钝了
that disabled people can also be dicks?
他这么对那个姑娘是不公平的
What he's doing now to that girl isn't fair.
分手是她提出来的
The break was her idea.
她现在觉得他们俩又重归于好了
And now she thinks they're back together.
他是个又怕  又病  又瞎的孩子
He's a scared, sick, blind kid
不想独自住院
who doesn't want to be alone.
你难道不明白吗
You really don't get that?
我明白  但是
I do, but...
什么东西
What is it?
对他和朴克都不是好消息
Not good news for him... or Park.
朴克呢
Where's Park?
威尔森在照顾她呢
Wilson's babysitting her.
如果和她说起她可能会有永久性脑损伤
Talking about the fact that she could have
可能会让她乐半天呢
permanent brain damage might bum her trip out a little bit.
黑点并不意味着脑损伤啊
A dark spot doesn't necessarily equal brain damage.
可能是与他失明相关的
It could be a congenital malformation
先天畸形
connected with his blindness
或者是肿瘤
or a tumor.
-是血凝块  -没错
- A clot. - Exactly.
我们得再做次扫描同时注入染色剂来找出..
We need to do another scan, but inject dye and figure out--
我说的是血凝块
I said "A clot,"
不是  或是血凝块
not "Or a clot."
就是个血凝块
It's a clot.
形成脑静脉窦血栓
Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis.
对朴克来说是好消息
Good news for Park.
我从没见过这么大的血凝块
I've never seen one present this large before.
这符合症状  当血凝块较小时
It fits. When it was smaller,
导致了初期的定向障碍
it caused his initial disorientation
和幻觉
and hallucinations.
当血凝块变大后就导致癫痫
As it grew larger, the seizures.
如果不治疗就会导致脑水肿甚至死亡
If left untreated, it leads to cerebral edema and death.
但什么导致了牙齿脱落呢
But what causes that and tooth loss?
以及易凝血状态  红斑狼疮
Any hyper-coagulable state. Lupus?
我以白塞综合症推翻你的红斑狼疮
I counter your lupus with Behcet's syndrome.
不可能  他没表现出任何早期症状
No, he doesn't have any of the earlier symptoms--
色盲  视野异常或者...
color blindness, abnormal visual fields or--
我们因为他是盲人就忽略了他的眼部问题
We've been ignoring his eyes because he's blind.
如果他以前没瞎现在也瞎了
Well, if he wasn't before, he would be by now.
做眼部检查进行确诊
Confirm with an eye exam,
用肝素治疗凝血块
start treatment with heparin for the clot.
干扰素和类固醇治疗白塞综合症
Interferon and steroids for the Behcet's.
住手  住手
No, no!
把我的牙齿还给我
Give me back my teeth!
朴克  听着  朴克
Park, listen. Park--
你个偷牙贼
You're a tooth thief!
不  不  住手  住手
No, no, no. Stop it, stop it!
回到沙发上去
Ki-ki-ki! Back on the couch.
你在对这可怜的女孩做什么
What are you doing to this poor girl?
不是看上去那样  她...
It's not what it looks like. She--Oh!
她因为酸中毒产生幻觉
She's tripping on acid.
上帝  你不能这么对待一个产生幻觉的人
Good lord, man, that's no way to treat a bad trip.
把椅子放下
Put the chair down.
你会伤到这个小可怜的
You'll end up hurting the poor wee thing.
亲爱的
Hello, darlin'.
我叫托马斯  这个美丽尤物叫布莱思
I'm Thomas, and this beautiful creature here is Blythe.
有什么我们能帮你的吗
Is there anything we can do to help you?
那只兔子偷了我的牙齿
That rabbit stole my teeth.
当然  不过我来告诉你他还干了什么
Of course he did, but I'll tell you what he's done.
他又把它们放了回去  现在你的牙齿比以前
He's put them back again, and they're twice as nice
漂亮多了
as they used to be.
你可以自己摸摸
You can feel them if you like.
感觉到了吗
See?
现在  让我们坐在这舒服的沙发上
Now, why don't we sit on this nice comfy couch,
来杯冰爽的饮料然后一起聊聊
have a nice cool drink and talk all about it.
你觉得好吗
Would you like that?
他对这种事有些经验
He's had some experience with things like this,
很久以前了
back in the day.
我记得我们俩...
As I recall, both of us--
不要在这说  亲爱的
Uh, not the time or the place, dear.
这就对了
There you are.
看  这就对了
See? There you are.
这人不可能和你有血缘关系
There's no way that guy's related to you.
有新鲜的瘢痕形成  基底两侧隆起
There's fresh scarring and swelling in both fundi,
左侧还有出血  豪斯是对的
and a bleed on the left. House was right.
是白塞综合症
It's Behcet's syndrome.
实话告诉我  医生
Give it to me straight, doc.
我还能再看到东西吗
Am I ever gonna see again?
这有点超出我们的管辖范围了
That's a little out of our jurisdiction.
我们需要在你的双眼上裹上遮盖物
We need to wrap a dressing over your eyes
以防止光线进入
to keep the light out.
对我不是问题
Not really a problem for me.
也许你看不见  但你的组织能感受到
You might not see it, but your tissue does.
这对消肿有会有帮助
It'll also help with the swelling.
这事就交给巧手的亚当斯医生了
I'll leave you in Dr. Adams' capable hands.
你认为我是个混蛋  对吗
You think I'm an ass, don't you?
我能通过你的呼吸声判断出来
I can tell by your breathing.
你不是很生气就是很胖
Either you're angry or fat.
我认为哄骗一个明显爱你
I think it's unfair that you're leading on a woman
关心你的女人是不公平的
who obviously loves and cares about you.
我也同样爱她关心她
I love and care about her too.
我们只是没法成为一对
But we just don't work together as a couple.
你得告诉她这点
You need to tell her that.
我会的
I'm going to.
我只是想用正确的方式做这件事
But I just want to do it the right way.
我不想她恨我
I don't want her to hate me.
如果她发现你给别的女人
When she finds out you bought an engagement ring
买了订婚戒指  那这个选项就是无稽之谈
for another woman, that option is out the window.
本来戒指是给她的
It was gonna be for her.
有什么变化吗
What changed?
她告诉我我们得分开一段时间
She told me we were going on a break.
我对此甚至没有发言权
I didn't even get a say in the matter.
她只是想让你想清楚两人的关系
She wanted you to be sure about your relationship.
我能想象那有多恼人
I can see how that would be annoying.
我情愿你只是生气而已
I think I liked it better when you were just breathing angrily.
她还是把我当成在大学时遇到的那个
She still sees me as the same sheltered,
需要被保护的失明土包子
blind geek she met in college.
多数时候她更像我妈
Most of the time she acts more like my mother
而不是女朋友
than my girlfriend.
我想让她嫁给我
I asked her to marry me.
她却告诉我我需要先跟别人约会
She tells me I need to date somebody else first.
我更希望她直接甩了我
I'd rather she just dumped me.
至少我能理解
At least that I can understand.
这么说你是被伤得太深
So you were hurt so much
才要娶你后来遇到的女人吗
you had to marry the next woman you met?
茱莉看到的不是过去的我
Julie doesn't see me as I was,
而是现在的我
but for who I am now.
她相信我能够自己做决定
She trusts me to make my own decisions
并且能帮助她做一些决定
and to help her with hers.
我人生中第一次
For the first time in my life,
有被人需要的感觉
I have somebody who needs me...
而不是需要别人照顾
instead of the other way around.
她终于睡着了
Ah, she finally fell asleep.
我估计过几个小时她就会好了
I think she'll be fine in a couple of hours.
你怎么知道如何对待酸中毒产生幻觉的人
How do you know about handling a bad acid trip?
你园艺俱乐部的朋友们又做实验了
Friends in your gardening club been experimenting again?
我也年轻过
I was young once.
托马斯东拼西凑做的小相册
A little scrapbook that Thomas threw together.
他甚至有几张你小时候的照片
He even has a couple of pictures of you as a child.
要知道自打格雷戈出生时我就认识他了
And I've known Greg almost since he was born, you know.
我和他父亲就像兄弟一样
His father and I were like brothers.
那时候我还是海军牧师
I was a navy chaplain in those days.
不过在六十年代就离开了
I left the service in the late '60s.
我认为他父亲不会原谅我
I don't think his dad ever forgave me
反对战争
for protesting the war.
当然  如果他知道布莱思也被我拖下水...
Of course, if he knew I'd got Blythe involved...
你反对战争吗  什么时候
You protested the war? When?
你那时还是小孩
You were a child.
我并没有告诉你我的全部
I didn't share my entire schedule with you.
我们知道如果告诉你  你就会去告状
We knew if we told you, you'd tell him,
他就会把我们都杀了
and he'd kill us both.
他是海军  这是彻头彻尾的背叛
He was a marine. It was the ultimate betrayal.
双重背叛
Penultimate.
亲爱的  我想我们该回酒店了
Sweetheart, I think we need to get back to the hotel.
威尔森  很高兴见到你
Wilson, it's been a real pleasure.
你是对的  这样太正式了
You're right. Much too formal.
来吧  小伙子
Come here, lad.
我们终于是一家人了
We're practically family now.
孩子们晚上见
We'll see you boys tonight.
走好
Keep sharp.
我邀请了他们一起吃晚饭
I invited them out to dinner.
说是你的主意
Told them it was your idea.
吸管在这儿
Straw.
我知道我们达成过一致  不过问分手期间
I know we agreed that whatever happened on break
发生的事情  我不指望你
would stay on break, and I don't expect you
告诉我你的经历
to talk about yours.
但是我想让你知道  这期间我没和别人约会过
But I just want you to know that there was no one else.
我想你想得好苦
I missed you so much,
都几乎不怎么和朋友们见面
I barely even saw my own friends.
我们能合好我太高兴了
I'm just so glad it's finally over.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
他怎么了
What's happening to him?
他不会有事吧
Is he going to be okay?
我要和同事们讨论下
I'm going to need to discuss that with my colleagues.
我们得谈谈
We have to talk.
不  你需要休息
No, you need to rest.
有些事得和你说
I have to tell you about...
一些在分手期间发生的事
About what happened on break.
以后吧  你现在躺着休息...
Later. You just lie back and relax...
别说了  梅丽莎
Stop it, Melissa!
别对我发号施令了
Just stop telling me what I need,
就这么听我说次话行吗
and listen for once, okay?
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
好尴尬
Embarrassed.
我还是有些分不清哪些是现实
I'm still not sure what was real
哪些是幻觉
or what I hallucinated.
你之前是不是想吻我
Did you try to kiss me?
那你呢
What about you?
他目前情况稳定了
He's stabilized for the moment.
咳血
Coughing up blood.
并不代表他得的是其他疾病
That doesn't really change anything.
咳血是白塞氏综合症的症状之一
Hemoptysis is a symptom of Behcet's.
但是我们的治疗应该会让他好转
Except our treatment should make him better,
而不是恶化
not worse.
也有恶化的可能
It could be doing both.
通过治疗  溶解他脑子里的血块
Our treatment breaks down his clot in his head,
这是正常情况  但是有一块血块分离出来
like it's supposed to, except a piece broke off
到了他肺部的动脉里
and traveled to one of his arteries in his lungs.
别的不说  我们应该增加肝素的剂量
If anything, we need to increase the Heparin
防止形成新的血块
to prevent further clots from forming.
如此这样的话  如果他出现流血症状
If we do that and he starts hemorrhaging,
我们就无法给他止血
we won't be able to stop the bleeding.
但如果不这么做  下一个血块
If we don't do that, the next clot
就可能引起心脏病或者是中风
could cause a heart attack or a stroke.
按照朴克的做法  他至少还有活命的机会
Park's way, he at least has a shot at living.
给他的肺部做CT  加大肝素剂量
CT his lungs to confirm, and up the dose.
她年轻又漂亮  会走出低谷的
She's young and hot. She'll bounce back.
37公斤
82 pounds.
类似的分手后我长了那么多的肉
How much weight I put on when my break ended the same way.
别人开始叫我朴太膘了
People were calling me park-ing-lot.
快九点了
Almost 9:00.
我觉得你儿子要放我们鸽子了
I think your boy is gonna stand us up.
不会的  他会来的
No, no, he'll be here.
差点就撞见我们滚床单
Practically walked in on us having sex.
上天啊  如果给我看到我妈干这事儿
God, if I saw my mother doing that,
我会把眼睛都挖出来
I'd claw my own eyes out.
当然啦  她远没有你性感
Of course, she was nowhere near as attractive as you.
事实上  她非常胖
Horribly fat, as a matter of fact.
妈...
Mother...
我妈的炮友
Guy sleeping with my mother,
这位是我妻子  多米尼卡
this is Dominika, my wife.
见到你真是太好了
It's so nice to be meeting you.
格雷戈里告诉我  你出生在弗吉尼亚的里士满
Gregory tells me that you were born in Richmond, Virginia.
你父亲是个裁缝  老是偷顾客的东西
And your father was a tailor who stole from his clients.
是詹姆斯建议我
James has persuaded me of the value
应该对家人开诚布公  毫无保留
of openness and honesty in relationships.
残疾人我们见的多了  但是...
We see people with disabilities all the time, but...
但还是很难理解他们
seeing and understanding aren't always the same thing.
你是在和我说话  还是在发微博
Are you talking to me or writing a facebook post?
我想说的是  我们原可以早点发现
I'm saying we should have picked up on the degeneration
他眼睛的病变
in his eyes sooner.
却忽视了  就因为
We ignored them because we assumed
我们压根就没考虑盲人的眼睛
they weren't even part of the equation.
同时  我发现  从理性角度
I also realized, intellectually,
我能够理解残疾的痛苦
I may understand what it means to be disabled,
但从感性角度  我无从知晓
but emotionally, I didn't have a clue.
显然  他的女朋友也没体会到
Apparently, his girlfriend didn't either.
这么说你现在站到他的立场上了
So you're back on his side?
不是谁的立场  而是换个角度看问题
It's not a side. It's a perspective.
他只是希望能被当作成年人看待
He just wants to be treated like an adult.
能自主做决定
Make his own decisions.
我可能不完全赞同他的那些决定
I may not agree with all of them,
但我有什么资格去评判他啊
but how the hell can I judge him?
我完全赞同你的看法
I'm sure that's exactly what disabled people want,
残疾人就该被视为怪胎
to be treated like completely foreign entities,
无法理解  无从评判
incapable of being judged and understood.
朴克说对了  是有血块
Park was right about the clot.
希望抗凝血剂能保住他的命
Hopefully the anticoagulants keep it from killing him.
奇数夜她睡沙发
She gets the couch on the odd nights,
偶数夜我睡床上
and I get the bed on evens.
作为诈骗罪的奖励
In exchange for a federal felony,
她拿到了绿卡
she gets a green card,
我有了名女佣
and I get a live-in maid.
太好了
Good for you.
我们国家的移民政策就是个天大的笑话
The immigration policy in this country is a travesty.
逼着那么美丽的姑娘为了留下来使尽骗术
It forces people to lie just so nice people can stay here.
谢谢你这么说   爸
Thank you...Dad.
你能同意我很感激
I'm grateful you approve.
还要告诉你们  我去年  不在非洲
You should also know that I was not in Africa the last year.
你进监狱了
You were in jail.
自打你搬到这边  我就开始关注
I've been reading the Princeton Police Blotter
普利斯顿的警方纪实
ever since you moved here.
恐怕我也对你说了谎
And I'm afraid I haven't been truthful with you either.
这事儿我很早以前就想告诉你了
And I've wanted to tell you this for a very long time.
我和托马斯...
Thomas and I...
在你父亲过世两月后就结婚了
We got married two months after your father passed away.
要知道
You understand,
我们不想让你觉得
we didn't want you to think we were disrespecting
我们对你父亲有任何的不敬
the memory of your father.
还有其他秘密
And...is there another secret
要和我分享的吗
that you want to share with me?
没了
No.
再没有和我人生
There's nothing you think might be relevant
有关的事情了吗
to my life?
-比如说什么呢  -我不知道
- Like...What? - I don't know.
我记得
Just off the top of my head,
我给我爸做过DNA测试
something like I DNA-tested my dad
发现他不是我的生父
and found that he was not my biological father.
你才是
You are.
那不可能
That's impossible.
人会说谎  但是胎记不会
People lie. Birthmarks don't.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
你说过他是个早产儿的
You told me he was a premie.
这个疯子竟然是我儿子
This bloody lunatic is my son!
他不是疯子
He's not a lunatic.
这么多年了  你早该告诉我
All those years you could have told me.
我原本可以尽父责
I could have done things.
或许就可以改变你儿子的人生
That could have made a difference in the boy's life.
我觉得大家都该冷静下
I think we should all just calm down.
看看他坐着那德行
Look at him sitting there...
一个嗑药的反社会
A pill-popping sociopath!
你把他人生给毁得
If you wanted to screw up his life,
也太彻底了吧
you couldn't have done it better.
这点他说得没错  老妈
He's got you there, mom.
他是世界上最受推崇的医生之一
He's one of the most well-respected doctors in the world.
他救治的人你数都数不清
He's saved more lives than you can count.
马上向他道歉  不然我发誓
Now, you apologize to him, or I swear,
托马斯  你休想再见到我
wou will never see me again, Thomas.
我受不了了
I can't deal with this anymore.
他竟然是我儿子
He's my son?
我得出去透口气
I'm having a bloody breath of fresh air,
就这样
that's what I'm doing.
谁要吃甜点
So, who's for dessert?
谁来帮帮我
Somebody help me!
-快来人  - 威尔
- Somebody-- - Will?
我们是亚当斯医生和奇斯医生
It's Dr. Adams and Dr. Chase.
-我们需要知道...  -眼睛  我的眼睛
- We just need to know... - My eyes! My eyes!
像着了火一样
It feels like it's on fire!
这不是白塞氏病
It's not Behcet's.
白塞氏病不会发生这样的组织坏死
It doesn't necrotize tissue like this.
我认为是化脓性链球菌
I think it's streptococcus pyogenes.
但我们已经给他用过广谱抗生素了
Except we've already treated him with broad spectrum antibiotics.
细菌不该扩散  而应该死亡
It shouldn't be spreading. It should be dying.
只能说明这是耐药菌
Just means it's drug-resistant.
我们必须在坏疽发生之前摘除剩余的眼组织
We need to remove what's left of his eyes Before the gangrene sets in.
形态看似细菌  行为也类似细菌
It's something that looks and acts like a bacteria
但却不是细菌
but isn't one.
-可能是病毒感染  -不  不可能
- Could be viral. - No, it couldn't.
坏死组织中没有任何病毒标志
There's no evidence of viral markers in the necrotized tissue.
给我看看你们昨晚拍的
Let me see that image you took last night
肺部凝块图像
of the clot in his lung.
这不是脑部凝块的一部分
That's not a piece of the clot from his brain.
这才是感染点
That's the point of infection.
毛霉菌病
Mucormycosis.
他吸入了孢子
He breathed in the spores,
病菌在他体内生长扩散
it's been growing and spreading ever since.
真菌感染会这么快吗
A fungal infection spreading this fast?
这孩子有糖尿病
Kid's a diabetic.
他的免疫系统已经瘫痪了
He already has a compromised immune system.
豪斯说的对  眼组织样本上布满了真菌
He's right. This sample from his eyes is crawling with it.
用两性霉素B治疗
Treat with Amphotericin B.
在认为是细菌感染的时候
We treated him with gentamicin
我们已经用了庆大霉素
when we thought it was bacterial,
这意味着治疗剂量的两性霉素B
Which means the dose of Amphotericin B we'll need
很可能会导致他耳聋
to cure him will probably leave him deaf.
抱歉  "治疗剂量"后面说了什么
Sorry, I stopped listening after you said
我都没听
"the dose we'll need to cure him."
又聋又瞎
Blind and deaf?
我宁愿死
I'd rather be dead.
不治疗你会死的
You will be.
那样我能"活"下去
I can live with that.
你就是听不懂我的笑话
You never did get my humor.
有可能你不会完全丧失听觉
There's a chance your hearing won't be completely gone.
有多大可能
How much of a chance?
很小
A small one.
但还是有可能
But a chance.
我...我拒绝接受治疗
I'm--I'm refusing treatment.
你不了解  我的生活已经有多艰难
You don't know how hard things are already for me.
再难我承受不来
I can't handle any more.
不能够了
I can't.
你好
Oh, hi.
我是来道歉的
I'm here to apologize.
得知消息我本该表现得更...
I could have handled the news with more...
沉着
aplomb?
我有个儿子  这是非常好的事情
I have a son. That's great news.
她还教你说什么了
What else did she tell you to say?
你不是疯子  也不是个错误
You're not a lunatic, you're not a mistake.
我一直都不喜欢你那位朋友  我父亲
I never liked your friend... my father.
他这人有时候的确过于激烈
Well, he could be a bit intense at times.
可是与你不同  我尊重他
But unlike you, I did respect him.
你尊重你母亲吗
Do you respect your mother?
我和你一样尊重她
Well, we do have that in common.
而且我们都爱她
And we all love her.
所以我们都没得选择  不是吗
So we don't have much choice, do we?
儿子  晚餐时见
Son, see you at dinner.
威尔  是我
Will, it's me.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
认为我是王八蛋的医生
The doctor who thinks I'm an ass
让你来劝我活下去
wants you to convince me to live.
是的
Yes.
-没用的  -我知道
- It won't work. - I know.
所以我不会劝你
So I won't.
你有这么气我
Wow. You're that angry?
我替你做的决定已经够多了
I've made enough decisions for you.
这是你的生活
This is your life.
你为什么回来
Why'd you come back?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
我想要陪你走过最后一段
And I want to be with you for as long as I can.
梅丽莎  我好害怕
Melissa, I'm so scared.
我也怕
Me too.
我会永远爱你
I'll always love you.
即便我聋了吗
Even if I was deaf?
即便发生任何事情
Even if anything.
起效了吗
Is it working?
他的病情仍然非常严重
He's still very ill,
不过如果按目前的治疗效果发展
but if he keeps responding the way he has been,
他应该会好起来的
he should be fine.
-他的听觉呢  -完全丧失
- And his hearing? - It's gone.
现在还无法确定是不是永久性的
We don't know yet if it'll be permanent.
梅丽莎  是你吗
Melissa? Is that you?
我们捏他的手来表示
We've been squeezing his hand,
一下表示是  两下表示不是
once for yes, twice for no.
可以问你一件事吗
Can I ask you something?
如果你捏不  我完全能理解
I completely understand if you squeeze no.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
不要这个时候不回答我
Don't leave me hanging, now.
我愿意
Yes.
我愿意  当然愿意
Yes! Of course, yes!
我听到了  你说愿意  是吗
I--I heard that. You said yes, right?
-我愿意  -你说愿意了
- Yes! - You said yes.
你打算等多久才告诉我
How long are you gonna wait until you tell me?
圣诞老人不存在我早告诉你了
I thought we already had the Santa Claus talk.
你在餐厅偷拿了托马斯的叉子
You don't think I saw you steal Thomas' fork
你以为我没看见
from the restaurant?
我偷他的叉子做什么
Why would I do that?
验他的DNA
For his DNA.
那个...  你还...
That's... that's...
真有观察力
very observant of you.
看吧  你比你装作的要更像我
See, you're more me than you pretend.
事实真相你非要确认不可
You had to know for sure.
所以你需要证据
So you needed proof.
而你没有告诉我结果
The fact that you haven't told me
只可能是因为...
can only mean...
他也不是你父亲
He isn't your father either.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你知道这意味着什么
You know what that means.
你妈是个荡妇
Your mom's a slut.
没错
That...
还有就是  她不像我一直以为的那样无趣
And... She's not as boring as I thought she was.